Basit Ali



alib4111@gmail.com



+923087310740



linkedin.com/in/basit-ali-04a790151



https://www.codingwithbasit.com

Summary

I am an experienced Web Developer with more than 4 years of experience building web applications using different technologies. I have vast experience in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, NodeJs, Express, MongoDB, GraphQL, and also in relational databases.

I am a freelance web developer currently. With coding experience, I also have experience of teaching students across the globe. I have taught almost 400 students from different countries across the globe all online.

Experience



Upwork Freelance Web Developer

Upwork

Aug 2022 - Present (6 months)

Recently joined work and as of now I have worked with 3 different clients on Upwork with 96% success rate.

Upwork Profile Link:

https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~01841a2ae6fb993896

f Freelance Web Developer - Level2

Fiverr

Jun 2019 - Present (3 years 8 months)

I joined Fiverr in 2019 after Covid Pandemic. And since then, I have been working there as freelance web developer and coding tutor there with more than 175 reviews on different accounts and 400+ clients and students worldwide.

Learned a lot during this journey, been able to meet different people across the globe and worked with companies like My Therapy Tool based in US and Foodini in Australia and many more.

https://www.staging.webapp.getfoodini.com

Fiverr Profile Link:

https://www.fiverr.com/share/kA4WQw

Chief Executive Officer at bobisoft

bobisoft

Sep 2020 - Present (2 years 5 months)

I created this company. My company servers businesses by giving software solutions of almost all kinds.

Freelance Web Developer

Fivver.com

Mar 2019 - Present (3 years 11 months)

.NET Developer

PRINTMIS

Jul 2019 - Apr 2020 (10 months)

if you know how to code, you can, no matter what the syntax is.

Education



Bahauddin Zakariya University

Master of Computer Science, Computer Science

2016 - 2018

I am a freelance web developer having experience in WordPress, HTML, jQuery, JavaScript, CSS and Bootstrap. I work on www.fiverr.com. If you want your business to grow and nurture in good pace then contact me I would help you in the best possible way by developing very-helpful websites for your organization.

Licenses & Certifications

Build Responsive Real World Websites with HTML and CSS - Udemy

Skills

React.js • Node.js • Express.js • JavaScript • HTML5 • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • REST APIs • GraphQL • MongoDB • SQL